# **Dmytro Karataiev**

adkdevelopment.com github.com/dmytroKarataiev linkedin.com/in/dmytrokarataiev

# **Summary:**

Android developer with portfolio of open-source applications published on Google Play and interested in the field of Machine Learning. Also have extensive experience in marketing, including successful portfolio management and new brands launches with focus on digital activities.

# **Technical Skills**

Languages: Java, Python.

Databases/Other: Realm, SQLite, Git/GitHub, Gradle.

Exposed to: JavaScript, PHP, CSS3.

# **Project Experience**

# Earthquake Survival – GitHub Page – Google Play

April 2016 - Present

- Earthquake monitoring application with survival information, notifications, auto syncs.
- Uses SyncAdapter, ContentProvider, Loaders, Maps, Locations, Geofences, Notifications.

# Flashlight with Morse – <u>GitHub Page</u> – <u>Google Play</u>

January 2016

- Flashlight application with simple design, fast speed, Morse code and Emergency Signal.
- Works as Service with all the tasks on background thread (Service, Camera2 API).

# Popular Movies - GitHub Page - Google Play

December 2015 - Present

- Fast and efficient client to The Movie Database with Search and Favorites functionality and tablet design.
- Uses RecyclerView, AsyncTasks, Fragments, Content Provider, Database, CursorAdapter, YouTube API.

# Connect Four Game – GitHub Page – Google Play

November 2015

- Hard solved Android game with different Al's, two-player mode.
- Real-Time Multiplayer, Achievements through Google Play Services.

#### Other projects

2015 - 2016

- XYZ Reader RSS reader with Material Design, <u>WatchFace for Android Wear</u> Used layouts, RxWear.
- <u>Build It Bigger</u> Joke-telling app with 2 flavours and GCE, Android and Java libraries, Tests.
- Barcode Scanner Google Vision API, Content Provider, Football Scores JobScheduler, Collection Widget.

# **Work Experience**

#### Yalantis – Android Intern

Dnipro, Ukraine | February 2016 – June 2016

- Created three Android applications with an increasing level of complexity.
- Used technologies: MVP Architecture, RxJava, Retrofit, Facebook API, Dagger 2, etc.
- Projects on the GitHub.

# **DANONE Nutricia** – Marketing, Strategy and Insights Manager

Kyiv, Ukraine | April 2013 - August 2014

- Managed portfolio of 3 brands, achieved 2<sup>nd</sup> position in the Value Market Share (+700bps Year on Year).
- Launched portfolio extension (new 9 SKU's +33%), managed Social Media campaigns.

#### **Unilever** – Brand Manager

Kyiv, Ukraine | July 2010 – April 2013

- Achieved 1<sup>st</sup> place in Volume/Value Market Shares (+1000bps), launched new brand, 40 additional SKU's.
- Managed several cross-country projects (Russia Ukraine Belarus), led workshops for sales team.

#### Education

<b>Udacity</b> – Mac	hine Learning	Engineer	Nanod	legree

exp. Sept 2016

**Udacity** – Android Nanodegree – <u>Verified Certificate</u>

April 2016

Taurida National University, Simferopol, Ukraine – Political Science, M.A., GPA 3.57

June 2010

#### **Certificates**

Coursera University of Michigan – Programming in Python (4 courses)
Coursera Stanford – Algorithms and Analysis (Part 1)
edX MIT – 6.00.1x, 6.00.2x Computer Science and Python Programming
edX Harvard CS50x – Intro to Computer Science

October 2015 – March 2016 October 2015 – December 2015 August 2015 – December 2015 July 2015 – November 2015

# **Honors and Activities**

Udacity Transcend Award – <u>Link</u>

June 2016

Volunteer at Julie Easton Art Studio

October 2014 – June 2015

Choice of the year award for the best brand in the market (2011, 2012)

December 2011, December 2012

First prize and diploma for the best paper – Moscow State University International Conference

April 2010